# **David Olivo**

"Fullstack Web Developer"

CABA, Argentina. (+54) 9 1124016394

**E-mail:** davidoar15@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** <u>David Olivo Rodríguez</u>

Portfolio: <a href="https://davidoar15.github.io/Portfolio/">https://davidoar15.github.io/Portfolio/</a> GitHub: <a href="Davidoar15">Davidoar15</a>

Full Stack Developer and Student in Information Systems Engineering at the National Technological University. I have experience in Front-End and Back-End development, using technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React/Redux, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL and MongoDB. I possess knowledge in agile methodologies (Scrum), GIT, data structures, algorithms, and frameworks. As an individual, I am committed, responsible, empathetic, resilient, honest, and helpful.

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

### FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER - PELOM APP

April 2024 - Present

### Intership

Participation in the improvement of the PELOM web application, a cutting-edge digital service that enhances customer service experience in restaurants, cafés, and bars by resolving issues. My activities include:

- Work with a multicultural team, using English as the language of communication.
- Read documentation about the project's Structuring, Workflow, Branch Creation, and Pull Requests, familiarizing myself with the code.
- Set up the project locally using Ubuntu and Docker.
- Enhance customized error pages (404, 401, 500) with multi-language support.
- Enable Google Maps links given an address.

### FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER - NESTIFY PLATFORM

February 2024 - March 2024

# Intership

Collaborate in the development of the Nestify platform on entrepreneurship and development for potential freelancers, offering courses, bootcamps, mentorship, and benefits for registered and logged-in users, as well as more personalized guidance and profile editing.

- Create a Mentorships Model for MongoDB Database.
- Create GET, POST, PUT and DELETE routes for CRUD operations on Mentorships, using JS, Node.js and Express.
- Collaborate in refactor Routes and Controllers in Backend.
- Be the main responsible for the implementation and flow of Stripe as a payment gateway for the acquisition of products / services on the plataform, sending and email to the user's email confirming the purchase and its details using Nodemailer, from Frontend to Backend.
- Participate in the design and logic within different React components with JS and SASS.
- Be present in the Daily meetings, report on the tasks completed and showcase demos of the progress made at the end of the week (Scrum methodology).
- Debug code and investigate relevant information to use (APIs, Documentation, etc).

# FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - PRODELEVATE

Jule 2023 - August 2023

# **Professional Practice**

Web system designed for product administration, management, and online sales. Its essence lies in providing a robust and efficient platform, aimed at enabling users to create and manage products, carry out sales, control inventory, and offer a seamless shopping experience for customers. I had an active involvement in:

- Model and build the plataform's Database using Sequelize and PostgreSQL.
- Create GET, POST, PUT and Delete routes for CRUD operations on Products, Users, Providers and Categories, using JavaScript, Node.js and Express.
- Implement User Local Authentication from both the Back and Front end using passport.
- Creation of informative plataform components: About Us, Privacy Policy, Terms & Conditions.
- Achieve responsive design.

Presentation: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ohP9JcM9b-8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ohP9JcM9b-8</a>

# **PROJECTS:**

### FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - POKÉMON

June 2023 - Jule 2023

# **Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp**

Design and develop a Single Page Application (SPA) about Pokémon where you can:

- Search for Pokémon and view their information.
- Sort them alphabetically or by stadistics.
- Filter them by type or origin.
- Create new Pokémon.

Front - End: JavaScript, HTML, CSS Modules, React, Redux.

Back - End: JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Sequelize, PostgreSQL.

Repository: https://github.com/Davidoar15/PI-Pokemon-by-David-Olivo

# FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - DISCORD CLONE

September 2023 - October 2023

### Self-taught experience

Design and develop a Discord clone that fulfills its core functionalities:

- Authentication with Clerk.
- Real-time messaging using Socket.io.
- Deleting and editing messages in real-time for all users.
- 1:1 Conversation and Video Calls between members.
- · Sending file attachments as messages using UploadThing.
- Member management (kick, guest/moderator role change).
- Generation of unique invitation links and functional invitation system.
- Infinite loading of messages in batches of 10 with Tanstack-query.
- Creation and customization of servers.
- Good user interface using Tailwind CSS and ShadcnUI.
- ORM using Prisma.
- Database using PlanetScale.
- Light / Dark mode.

Front - End: Next.js Client, TypeScript, React, Tailwind.

Back - End: Next.js Server, TypeScript, Socket.io, Prisma, MySQL.

Repository: https://github.com/Davidoar15/Discord-Clone

# **TECHNOLOGIES:**

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, JAVA, C++, Ruby.
- Frameworks Tools: React, Vue, Node.js, Express, Sequelize, Next.js, Ruby on Rails.
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Prisma, MongoDB.
- Tools: Git, Docker, Slack, Discord. Agile: Scrum.

# **PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION:**

- Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. 4 months of theorical and practical coursework. 2023.
- 4th Semester of Systems Engineering. Universidad Nacional Abierta, Venezuela. 2021 2023 (Not completed due to migration).
- 1st Level in Information Systems Engineering. National Technological University, Argentina. 2024 Present.

### **IDIOMAS:**

• English B2 – Upper Intermediate: <u>Document</u>